<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Excel and VBA macros on Vijay Waghmare</title>
    <link>https://vwaghmare111.github.io/excel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Excel and VBA macros on Vijay Waghmare</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vwaghmare111.github.io/excel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Integrated Borrowers Rating Model</title>
      <link>https://vwaghmare111.github.io/excel/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vwaghmare111.github.io/excel/project-1/</guid>
      <description>This is a demo version of the model made for RMA India. Full license of the model is with Risk Management Associates, Pune. India. Model is based on VBA macro for three different industries namely; manufacturing, trading, service. As financial ratios are different for each industry; Financial statement formats dynamically changes as per industry selected by the user on Cover page. Please read user instructions for details.
Link to the file</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MySQL with VBA macro</title>
      <link>https://vwaghmare111.github.io/excel/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vwaghmare111.github.io/excel/project-2/</guid>
      <description>ClassicModels.xlsm is a simple macro to extract data from MySQL database and load it on excel spreadsheet. It contains three macros;
 Extract list of tables from the database Load data from selected table on excel spreadsheet Clear loaded data and list of tables from excel spreadsheet  Copy MySQL ClassicModels database in below path. Please note, path might be different on your computer.
C:\ProgramData\MySQL\MySQL Server 8.0\Data
Enter server details on Worksheet 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Appraisal including sensitivity analysis with VBA macro</title>
      <link>https://vwaghmare111.github.io/excel/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vwaghmare111.github.io/excel/project-3/</guid>
      <description>Project appraisal with sensitivity and scenario analysis is not only crucial bankers and businesses to check financial feasibility of the project. Every project begins with estimated values of expenses, interest rates, income, inflation etc. Thus, testing sensitivity of capital budgeting tools such as Net Present Value (NPV), Internal Rate of Return (IRR) of estimated income against changes key estimated variables.
Quality Cables project contains sensitivity analysis along with Monte Carlo simulation with 100 paths.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Case study - Business analysis for a car insurance brokerage service</title>
      <link>https://vwaghmare111.github.io/excel/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vwaghmare111.github.io/excel/project-4/</guid>
      <description>This case study involves analyzing sample customers data with their demographics, broker, insurer, savings, and satisfcation using descriptive statistics, hypothesis testing, ANOVA test including simple effect analysis
Link to the file
Link to case study report</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Case study - Business analysis for a superstore</title>
      <link>https://vwaghmare111.github.io/excel/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vwaghmare111.github.io/excel/project-5/</guid>
      <description>This case study involves analyzing data for 150 superstores with financial performance, manager details, competitors, car space availibility, online presnce etc. Descriptive statistics, regression, ANOVA, interaction effect, logistic regression, and timeseries forecasting techniques are used in excel
Link to Case study
Link to the file
Link to case study report</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
